We will now move into the City Council meeting for today's day and time called order item 2.
As public input and then schedule personal appearances.
The only answer was to adjust the council on any of the agenda items.
It would be 9 out of 3 is consent agenda staff is recommending items 4 and 5 which is again claims and minutes for the council.
There are no questions.
We have a motion to approve.
And the second.
Second.
John.
Johnson.
Lewis.
I.
Forester.
Sure.
Item 6 is presentation of Restoration Award through the Coleman Theatre from Grand Gateway.
Mr. Panamaki and I, Tammy.
Hi.
Good. Thank you.
Thank you for having me here this evening.
It is a lot of pleasure.
On behalf of the U.S.
Pressure Department of the Department of Administration through the ACW,
3.
The assembled G.z.
To have a Coleman honour as one of their star of the site.
The projects.
The project as you well know was 28 years in the making.
There were a lot of people when I would be missed.
I started to be in all of them on the side of the building.
That came the student country for the citizens of the city of Manila and for all of the other
cany and parts even further than that.
So it's with my pleasure, sir.
Okay.
We're going to present this to you, the mayor.
Jim.
And something for you to hang?
Well, we also have the Chairman of the Friends of the Coleman here too.
Ha ha.
I'm there.
Well, really this award, I mean, it goes to, as you said, a lot of people that are with
us anymore, and a lot of people that are still here in the community, but the Friends of
the Coleman passed in President War, a very big part of making this happen.
So, a big thank you to them.
I know it says the city of Manila, but big thank you to the Friends of the Coleman also.
Okay.
Item 7 is a main contract with cost-link construction, a construction manager at Wisk for
the Civic Center renovation construction project established the guaranteed maximum price
ideal.
Okay.
Currently, the demo inside is complete, we do have some demo left on the roof as it
is not sorry, the other roof project.
Fringling is nearly complete because I got to begin this week regarding the roofing, more
expecting 7 semi-trailer loads of materials to kind of provide.
We will be staging in the northeastern of the South Parking Lot and logging out that first
north entrance.
But the South entrance will still be.
accessible to staff and the public.
We're also, as part of our executive,
the webinar right next week.
And in later this week, we're going to be selecting
our architect, selecting some finishes.
We'll work that together.
Stay on the worse, the target, the counter job.
And then, I'm not initially a related project,
but it does affect the flow of this building.
And in the next month, they have, you guys,
the council approved a contract with him later.
Earlier this year, I think it was a first of June.
And they were working with the schools,
and it just finished up with the schools.
So now they're ready to start our project.
We're waiting on bonds.
So the day we get those is the day that we start.
That project is reinstalling the stairs.
They give them the banquet room, too.
They're a parking lot there with fifth and new.
And it's also to make some ADA improvements
to the concrete from the utility office,
all the way west to the west parking lot.
And that should take, we're guessing 90 days or less,
but they have them three days, so there's a higher issue.
That's the update.
I can try to answer some questions.
Do you want to ask any questions?
I'm just curious if there's anything that materials that we don't have yet.
It might be in the path that Hurricane coming in Florida.
Yeah, that's a good question.
And they said that materials are all worked.
But we're home work doing this.
They should be in transition.
We're in transit to hear everything that we need to hold that.
So we're still.
I know they've got a big need in.
Oh yeah.
So I know the domains there.
Yes.
We're going to talk about it a little bit later in the meeting.
I've asked Tyler to do this, but that's one of the hold-ups right now
on replacing the traffic signals at B.J. Tunnel and Maine.
Because those aren't stock items.
Number one.
And then number two is they come from the Houston area.
And now all the things that have been damaged are being replaced.
So we'll give you a little more detail about some of our plans on that.
We're experiencing it in that area, Doug.
Would you make sure that something about that gets in the paper, too?
Because I've had several people ask me if there's a lot still to link in.
Yeah.
I kind of wanted myself to look at me too.
Okay.
So we're going to use this actual gym item.
In the original contract that the council signed with Crosse and Aslox,
CNAR, construction manager.
There's Article 2.2 stated that following the acceptance of the Guarantee Maximum Prize,
which you all people did a lot of a month ago,
the owner and construction manager shall execute the exact amount of the price and management.
I'm ending this agreement and then we'll supply a copy to our architect.
So we'll do that.
It just has to be better, we're actually
ending our contract with cross one, two,
including the actual G&B, which is 1.9 million,
5.4,000 per 1.9, 54, 367.
And it's just what we said we were going to do.
So dear, we had the original contract in America,
the number in there was kind of a placeholder
that was no number at all.
Knowing all of all, we were going to come back
and plug in the number, which we did last month,
and now we just need to plug a lot of stuff.
Any question going in there?
Do we have a motion to approve?
So moved.
Second? Second.
Go call please?
With I, Weston, Forester, Johnson.
All right, thanks, Jill.
I had a made-off-right city manager to approve
change orders to the Civic Center renovation construction
of the hard day, as long as they do not exceed,
increase the council approve, again, and take maximum price.
And that's start wearing my glasses.
I lost my glasses, so I guess I have these leaders.
Anyway, so questions or being that huge,
those names next to it, if you want to talk about that at all,
or well, it's pretty simple, I think, from time to time,
as we go through these proceedings of the renovation,
there's going to be a need for certain decisions to be made,
which it would not be time or cost-effective to come
to the council to have every one of these names.
And as long as they're not going to increase the cost,
the idea is for you to authorize the city manager
to be able to make those decisions so that we can keep things moving
in this renovation process.
So I'll kind of liken it to the stadium project.
They would use the term value engineering,
but there were times when we had that fixed cost,
and this was across and also, the changes were necessary.
And if the price over here went up, then we said,
okay, you go back to drawing board and figure out
where you can save some money over here.
So the total project price did increase at all,
but we had to make changes.
And I'm certainly comfortable with that again.
I don't think if there were anything that was really significant
that we would want to know about it.
I don't know that we can really establish a dollar threshold,
but I just think we want to be in the loop
if there's anything that's significant.
Yeah, as a prime example, just recently,
we've had an issue of a couple of mis-measurements
that were done by our architectural firm.
And they are correcting it and they accepted it.
So that might have a little bit of a change order in relationship
to it, but actually would be a decrease in cost of the city.
So it not all change orders mean there are increases.
So I think that needs to be for the record.
But I agree with the measures.
if you're saying it's significant, so sure.
I feel pretty comfortable that you're reach out and you can let us know, right?
So, in the other questions are concerns, we have a second.
Second, roll call, please.
Johnson, forster, western, Lewis, I chose.
I am not in discussion if the polls changes to municipal court, fine, schedule, and then
they'll know on about eight or nine items following that, that are, I guess, the most specific
carrying is that.
Well, the eight or nine that follow are going to be bends, and you might remember in our last
study session, we were talking about some potential changes that are coming up.
Carry contacted me when we put this agenda together.
She basically, I'm ready to continue talking about some of these to get into place.
So, carry a checker here, and I'm going to let carry, take it from here, and then bend
and we'll handle those other items that relate to those two state questions, 780 and 781,
and Ben will explain this.
Carry before you start, Mickey, you have a specific question, you want?
I came in late to our study session last time, and on the avoiding the road block, feathered
to stop at road block.
I know there was something that was not driving around a road block.
Could you give me more detail on that?
Because I was either likened, misted, or...
I'm not sure if you can write that, if you wish, you know, somebody runs a road block, but nine
times out of 10, what happens since someone runs a road block, they might have to throw in you.
Usually, if we get to take it that someone is avoiding a road block, it's because we drove through
the Taco Bell parking lot because they didn't want that.
So, where is it on, which, what is the, what is the ordinance for driving through a
road, standing in the water, when you go around a road block?
That is the avoiding the work of safety zone, the violating the work of safety zone, it is, unfortunately,
to rent your driving ordinance on the side.
And that is a five hundred dollar.
I just know when people do that, they put our people, our fire department, our police department,
our first responders at risk, and I knew there was something there, and I mean, I mean,
I thought pretty sure it wasn't the avoiding the road block that I knew there was something there.
Right, yeah.
I feel like you're just stop at road block.
That's like, if you're just stop at a road block, it's like trying to, like, miss a red light and
go in through a parking lot at Walgreens, maybe.
Maybe it's more like if they have one of you, I check stop on, like, okay.
Okay.
I think the guy would record that, because I was using one set there at the block.
Okay, stop.
That's essentially what I'm here for tonight, because I just got this list that I'm off of
and it's a lot of information, and so I wanted to give you a chance.
to look at over and get high questions with that,
and to search, to get high suggestions,
they need to go through things and not read the things
something is too much.
That's what we want to do.
Kerry's or anything that you and working with Chuck
are others to have it modified since we discuss this
a certain month ago.
Okay.
I guess my question is, why do you reevaluate it
and take them down?
Is it because you felt like we're just too hard on the funds?
It's the majority of the ones that can't get up.
Can't get up because our Lord,
city wanted to just set up so that there was not
a specific fine attached to something
when the ordinance was going to place the default
of this library of dollars.
So we had a number of things like the district's walking
outside the crosswalk, or basically equipment
that didn't have a fine amount attached to it.
And so people are getting this ticket
and 500 dollar fine attached to it.
And trust me, they're not having that.
Yeah, that's a B-bit Chuck Actress.
Charges of that when it comes to court because it doesn't.
But basically what we're doing was going to fill me in and sign,
okay, the cleaning tax sign that the map is
and not just let that be all the way down there.
Kerry did the $500 was that also a trigger
that had something to do with district court
that was an unrelated thing.
I remember there was an issue about that.
But the original reason that 500 dollars was
put in there is at the time that that ordinance was written.
500 dollars was the cap on any kind of traffic
related issue.
The cap now is set number 50.
However, there is the fact that once you pass that $500 per show
of on any sign, we are required to give them
the district court.
An option for a jury trial, right?
We have to give the jury trial unless they
wait and rise.
So now you're talking about some significant money
in time out by and that sort of thing.
So we kind of tried.
So it was the default, but it was also a trigger for a jury trial.
I think, okay.
Any other questions or concerns?
I have a lot to do with the rule.
We've got it.
You're okay.
I have to be a friend that I'm talking about.
You're fine.
I have a little bit of texting, but is that the only one
that's mandated by the state of the day?
There you go.
I see that.
There's a 20-hour ticket thousand and a big one today.
So it's texting, well, the duty of the notion
that's a hundred dollars.
And those are the rule that states of the evening,
which are the rule for me.
Is the texting a moving violation?
Yes.
It goes into the state.
It does not go under the record, but they track it.
It just like C.C.L. C.L.C.L. was in the state
and you won't see it under the record.
Now you have phone calls sometimes.
Where it's I'm driving now.
I'm not texting, but I'm talking.
Is that going to fall under the same?
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha
If you have a C.C.L., yeah, it can.
Right now, I believe the way that's
accepted is ready.
It's just strictly.
texting. So it's the office search judgment call, what you're actually
you know what I'm saying. You know what I'm saying? You're right here with that because
the officer all you can see is that you've got that funny in your hand. And oh yes it's really
not what you're doing. Actually we don't really get that many texting violations. So I'm
going to be a hidden based on the few we get that the officers really have to be pretty
sure that they're texting before they're right. There's a significant and
force my problem.
Well my personal experience kind of like duh, does I make it the green button?
To put it on speaker and listen to it, but if I'm talking to you, I'm talking to you. I'm
touching my phone. He wouldn't know. I've thought about that with all of that.
Well I think we all support the spirit of it because you've taken figure out a way
to pop the link. You see what's important if you have a CDL. What do you mean by that?
If you're driving in a conversion motor vehicle and you have a CDL, the state is a real
more picky about that texting or using it. Actually I think it's legal as using a
handheld device bomb or anything like a commercial motor vehicle. So it's written just a little bit
differently. So there's two different standards levels on the state statute part of it.
Okay. I've got an animal control question and I'll try to answer that one.
This is not going to be easy, but I know it says a vicious dog. Okay. I'll give you scenario.
My neighbor had their fluffy dog lady and next to him was the man with the rot
wire and the rot wire would grow. Anybody that came home growled at me and the
neighbor's dog was on the leash to rot wire and broke the leash when overkilled it.
There again, how do you determine if it's a vicious dog without you know, it's too late now.
Generally the officers won't ride a vicious animal charge unless a person or an animal has been
been broken. That's the criteria for riding the tickets. If it got one of my grandkids,
I've probably been seeing the cheap.
That's what they ride the ticket and then it comes to court.
The check does he has a dress and depending on if on the situation, if it's severe enough,
he might order the dog with it.
It's a first time issue and we haven't had prior issues with the dog in the morning
that this is your only opportunity to pick it up as again I am before or the dog is so
So he has the option to do that. Okay, should we call if it and it usually the dog was placed outside after hours after the animal control had gotten off
You know who I'm talking to
One other thing I want to mention
You know, we're talking about fines and all that then and I think that's kind of getting up to say something
It's currently working on another aspect of all these changes
We're going to be looking at our animal control organs and a lot of that will deal with vicious animals
How many animals people have things such as that? So that's kind of like a whole different subject is coming your way
Absolutely, I agree. You know, it's too late then and
Anyway, I'd like to ask a question
Any other questions for caring?
I'd like to say that you will see this again probably a fairly soon coming you know, maybe our first meeting in October
But it will be an item then the last thing to do up the change actually
So you could still ask questions at that time, but then we'll have an item on there asking you to agree
Or you want to be able to click on the phone
And so I think you're interested in a great job going through the front of the institutions about having this policy and how to be registered
It's a pretty fair amount of things
There's always had to be, you know, really, I do. I have the ability to be in certain circumstances
Cut to find out what it can is as high as it is if you want it
So you have to be with it
If somebody comes up with something, they question that out of the center of that for a suggestion for you
I was calling you the word before we actually get to the adoption
I think I have to try to get to a lawyer question
All right, thank you
Thank you, thanks for all the hard work
Item 10
Through 50 bin
I'll show you star with 10 coordinates
2007 dash 10
I'm not going to read the whole thing, but it deals with sending them out of general penalties for criminal violations
So, one of the things that I was tasked with was bringing our ordinances into compliance
or to match up with what the state did when the voters approved, State Question 7-8.
And that basically is what I don't live in the through 17 days.
But item 10, in looking at that item, a gen item 10, is our general statute that sits out the parameters
of what the offenses could potentially carry.
And following on the other conversation about why we set the cap at 500 from what I gathered
at the planning meeting, is that was kind of the feeling of the counsel that that's what we wanted to do.
So, that's what we're addressing in item number 10, we're reducing the maximum fine from $800 to $500.
And that, in essence, is the main thing that we're accomplishing there.
Should be let me ask, I understand there were really two parts of the $500, when Kerry was talking about it.
But she said, one of them, the state has raised to $700 to $750.
The trigger for the jury trial is it still $500 at that number remaining the same.
So, we're predicating this on that number still.
You know, it's a slippery slope to say that that's what is guiding this exclusively.
But it does play a part in reducing the maximum fine to $500.
And in the state language, it has a fine in excess of $500.
So, it could $500 and one penny then triggers the right to a jury.
Now, let me, of course, state that, obviously, the judge doesn't have to go up to $500.
And in any individual ordinance that's outlining what is going to be a crime in the city of Miami, we can set a particular punishment there.
This ordinance applies when there is not a specific punishment set out with a particular crime.
And you'll see from all of these others that we're going to look at that they all do have a specified.
So, you've tried to deal with the most frequently occurring situations, but there's something kind of out of the ordinary.
And this is the default. That would be the defect.
Right.
And we have everything you can see.
So if you can have that, they are all going to have to find it out.
But there will be a catch and we're going to point it to you.
Something that's written in the state statute that we're going to address in this case.
There's won't be able to find a catch.
Right.
But the problem is, is that our general ordinance set it at 500 or 800%.
And so that, even though that's not necessarily what we have in our bonding schedule, that's
the other issue is texting didn't exist 10 years ago.
Right.
And so something else, 10 years from now, will maybe an issue that we're not looking
about today.
Right.
So that is the essence of the agenda item number 10.
The others all stand from 780.
So for instance, in the agenda item 11,
we're matching our ordinance up with what state question 780.
780 addressed several different areas of crimes.
There are two that we're addressing here because we, they weren't actually 780 questions.
But the question was raised because of 780.
And there are fences that we have prosecuted in the past, as I understand it,
but we actually don't have an ordinance on it.
So we were kind of fudging perhaps on the ordinances.
So basically all of the rest of these are to match our ordinance with the current language of state law.
With the exception of the punishment, with the punishment being said that a maximum of $500
and no possibility of jail time for the effects.
Because if you have either one of those, then it causes the other problems that we're trying to avoid.
And as we discussed a little bit last time, without reading and finding a specific example here,
but if there is a violation that the judge or, I'm not sure if it would necessarily have to be the judge,
but staff determines we want the district court to handle that that can happen.
That is always the discretion that the police department has.
And obviously on the more serious crimes, those all go to the district court.
So we're not required to, if there's a file that, or we're not required to prosecute them in city court.
I mean, a typical example is a public inbox.
Those are typically tried.
addressed in city court, but when you have a repeat offender, you know, the pre-complired
miles person, those often go to the district court.
So continuing on on agenda item 13, that is a new municipal ordinance, but basically we're adopting
the state statute, and that's, I think, where it typically is going to happen, somebody walks
a ticket at a restaurant, that's essentially what it's aimed at, and then similarly agenda item
15 is also a new municipal ordinance, again, matching the state statute, and that's something
that drives off from the gas station without paying for their gas.
We've prosecuted those as I understand it in the court, but not under an ordinance that
specifically addresses it that way.
And item 17, 17 is, okay, yes, thank you.
So what most people thought, state question 780 was about exclusively was drugs, the basically
possession of any drug other than marijuana was a felony and under the oil law.
Now, under the new law, it's possession of any drug up to the amount of,
that would trigger it to be a trafficking offense is a misdemear.
And so this gives the city the opportunity to prosecute the possession, simple possession of any drug
in municipal court. There's been discussion with the judge and with the chief of police,
as well as with the district attorney's office about this.
You know, the question is, in what format or what venue are we going to best be able to address the
the problems that the individual has with regards to a drug possession issue,
the general thinking that we came.
But it's not setting concrete here is that a first time a fan's maybe a second time a
fan's we would address in city court but if again we get to somebody that's a repeat
offender even though it's still a misdemeanor a fan's you know we will send it over to district
court for them to deal with and try to provide the services that obviously at that point
the person needs and it doesn't matter what drug it is I don't know that I can't think
of any exceptions to that I don't remember anything I think it's any controlled
danger substance even prescription drugs that you don't have the right because that's right
we'll surprise of the given the opioid crisis as it's being described and there
wouldn't be a part of that so I know we need to go through the council's ready and approve
each one of these but I wanted to just be a chance to kind of give a brawl over you well
a lot of the plan was again just to further discuss it but not as good but give you the opportunity
to see what we're proposing is as the finished product and we'll come back again later and address
some questions that you may have on the by all odds you said something we'll go about to
the place where we had as the as the plan is described where law gives you the point is it's
shoplifting she fans and rest on body for the fifth time shoplifting where's that number at
the time or the only change that was made on the shoplifting is under the old
statute it was and for it to be a misdemeanor it had to be $500 value or less under the new law
because of 780 it's a thousand dollars or less so anything that any shoplifting over a thousand
dollars which actually is not not all that difficult for somebody to do that's going to go to
district court as a fellow so anything under the thousand dollars you know again I use the term
discretion of the police department and from my experience in the district attorney's office you know
they know when somebody's really got some issues even if it made
be their second time, or, and obviously if it's somebody's eighth time, they obviously
know that there's a problem there.
So, it leaves a lot of the discretion to the prosecutor, as well as to the police officers
that are involved, because the police officers came to just file it over in District Attorney's
office and not even take it to the prosecutor, the city prosecutor, but if they take it to the
city prosecutor and he's, well, you know, I know some other things about this individual,
so I'm going to decline it and ask them to go over to them.
What these two state questions are going to, and I already have caused a lot of issues and
a lot of problems that are out of our control.
We've had discussions about not necessarily a set number, but that we may have that person a couple
of times, and then after maybe the third or the fourth, they go to District.
One of the problems, for example, that they're saying this will probably eliminate drug courts,
because why go to a drug court?
You know, why try to get yourself clean if all you have to do is pay a fine and keep going.
When we're talking about fines, court fines, I make a very clear that this is not a revenue
race, or this is not something that we're just trying to get more money by these fines.
The whole idea is to try to have, you know, some type of justice to make sure that somebody
doesn't, isn't recidivism.
You know, that they might clean their act up, or try to have something where, okay, if you continue
this, there's going to be something worse that will happen.
This question kind of took away from the whole idea was what we're going to have fewer people
in prison for minor offenses.
We'll see if that happens.
I don't think it will.
So I'm hoping that maybe in the not too distant future, people understand what they did
though for, maybe we'll get it corrected.
Then what are the implications for an offender for, let's just say, shop, letting a misdemeanor
shop, letting a charge and a city court versus district court?
I mean, the fines, the range of fines the same, or is there under this ordinance, the range
of fine would be greater in district court than it would be here, but either way, restitution
is one of the components that the judge would typically order in case for problems like shoplifting.
There's really not any treatment options that they will either place.
Okay, other questions, I'll permit it.
But I guess once these changes are adopted.
I'm going to take a very direct initiative to chuck and carry too.
We'll just kind of go along and see what the caseload looks like and what can be handled
and what can't.
Maybe we take on a little bit more and maybe we, you know, wherever that line gets drawn,
and it's still, there's always the judge will have discretion, but I think within reason,
if we suddenly double the number of cases, we've got to figure out a way to deal with that.
So that'd be policy approach in the police department, and when it comes to filing the charges or whatever, okay?
I don't, so we've gone through pretty much every item individually, if you would take the time
to look at the ordinances that have been extracted and as I said, we'll see these again,
and we'll be asked to take action on them if not next month, certainly pretty soon.
I don't know if there's excuse me, 18, there's capital ventures, government relations, LLC, October
claim of $3,000.
I'm going to list him on that.
Okay?
Do we receive anything from him besides the bill every month?
Actually, Brian asked me that question earlier today and I think we'll ever do for a couple of reports,
and I've already let him know that we need to get that.
So he has been working on quite a number of projects for us, I want to show you with that.
But I would like to see what it does, I mean, I know we came to talk to him, but I would like
to see a monthly report of what it is he did in us.
And actually, that was promised to you, and it has a mental every guess, and we'll get that.
I mean, all we get is a bill every month.
Interesting.
We'll get here for a little feedback, but we don't very much.
We don't very much in writing.
Well, I don't get verbal feedback, I'd like to see something in writing to know.
I'm saying, we had it, and then I had that conversation also a day, I call it a contact
report, but whatever the term is, that we need something substantive that communicates
what's been going on.
Yeah.
It's great.
So that said, I will make a motion to approve the capital ventures, invoice for October.
Do you have a second?
Say, go call, please.
Shope.
Aye.
Borster.
Weston.
Aye.
Lewis.
No.
Johnson.
Did you need business?
Do you need anyone?
No.
Okay.
Item 20 staff reports are put in packets are in your vote, you know, we're in a vote during
the packet of available, and staff are available for questions if they're already.
Okay.
Any five years and I've been able to respond to that.
Actually.
Defenses now.
Yeah.
I was going to put Christy and Alicia on the spot, because we're about to finish up the dirt
work, and then we're going to start taking over the size.
I haven't had a chance to ask you today because you do a quick update both of you can you tag team?
I'm not sure.
On the EP demo, they have pretty much wrapped it up.
There's one small, smaller list of categories still need to tag.
They're doing a great one.
It's time to tag with them.
There's a lot of them.
They've got the story out there.
It's been a long time since we've got more small,
that the band-hole is done.
It's somehow disconnected.
It's great to go.
They've developed and they've removed the pants as we said.
And we've put them in the trapping, graphing it at least.
We expect to have it turned over or at least they didn't come back.
We've done it all this stuff this along with that.
We've also started at this week on the call as signing as far as getting the,
right in the top so we've got the field placed.
The contours are looking really, really good.
We made a few adjustments that were the same.
She follows the pattern.
So we have.
And so our contract that we contract with,
it's bringing in the top soil.
It's actually started this after today.
It's a good minute working on the road a little bit.
We start the hard.
And then we'll take him about two weeks.
All of that, all of the dirt that we contract with him.
And it's all out there that we see where we're at.
From there.
As far as the sea of an hour it did,
Ben and Chris have found.
I think we've got to do it.
Design bill for the.
Slashback we've got to go see an AR.
It's been put up.
September 25th is our deadline for our,
our sea of an hour to put their.
Our response is back in and we are working on getting the architect engineer.
The proposal for them to send back to us.
And we should have that.
We're having me Thursday about.
And with that they get me on.
Six and things like that.
And we're our processes on that.
And then that we're just going to call the process before.
So that is our slowest day.
Probably a little bit.
It's going to slow us down.
sometimes have to say they are a little bit, but all better to be slowed down in a little bit.
We're still not going to make next summer.
We haven't, we haven't got that form.
We're not going to make that, that didn't want to hurt.
So we were going to give a negative there.
So you're going to bring the baby back where you're going to throw.
We're doing.
We're doing a lot of good stuff.
We're doing good stuff.
At this time we're going to do it next summer.
Sorry.
We're going to give the baby back.
Oh, yeah.
We're not there yet.
If that's one of the reasons why we start to do and design buildings and see a AR so that when
the size handed over to us, we already have a bid and can get the contractor in place.
If something changes on this, can you keep us up there?
Or starting to see a slow-down prop, you know?
You don't feel like we're not going to do that.
Yeah, I'd like to know.
The thing that slow the whole process down was the amount of chat that they discovered.
Because in all seriousness, even if we have everything ready to go right now, we still couldn't do it because we haven't got the site to go.
Right.
So we're still okay as far as they're doing that.
We're not going to do that.
You've got some ways, you've got some ways,
you've got some ways, mounds that the darts not with stakes with little red.
I don't know, plastic on them.
What are those marking?
At the AP side?
Yeah.
I'm not sure.
I'm going to say that they probably marked the chat as still there.
Well, there's no doubt.
It might be, I thought maybe they might be, I'm trying to put my head around because, you know, it's facilities major there.
I didn't, I don't know what they are.
I don't know if it's access to a server liner.
But you see them as you drive by.
I'll just try and check it.
Yeah, they've been intentionally left there instead of leveled out.
So just curious.
We'll check it out.
Okay.
I had hands off on that because it is the EKS side.
And so we're trying to make sure that we're keeping that.
But let's keep that.
The EKS side.
Sorry.
Yeah, sorry.
Yeah.
Okay.
I just asked you to be there.
Say to be part of the patient.
Next morning, it gets not that because we have some related items that are going to affect that.
So if you would be there.
So I'm subject, but I, you know, I'm starting to see the crews out and about on the roads.
So far, I had it turned out to be a roadside.
Back up and go some other direction because I'm not sure which roads they're doing because they're everywhere.
Yeah.
Before the next meeting, can you, I would like, can love to let's update the public.
What they've done so far were, you know, the next steps.
To take you, if anybody can give you a little future out.
But I would like a little presentation or something of what they've done so far.
They will be out of here, fine.
Okay.
Then by then you'll have to clean the show whenever what they get covered.
Yeah, you sell.
We both on the website.
And it's always good to relay to the public because I've got it many of times.
I sure do love the rock.
And I think that's pretty that they just covered that nice asphalt that's already there in front of these people.
Sources.
They need to understand that there's a reason why that was put out.
I know you've covered it.
But I've never loved to make sure that.
And we do things that I don't make some effort trying to make, right?
Right.
Yeah.
Chuck Street looks real great, by the way.
I like it.
Thank you for doing that.
Any other staff reports?
Any announcements?
I've got one, if anybody else got one.
I just wanted to invite a lot of those.
We lost, got along here, but this past week.
I mean, Brian had the opportunity to serve on the city of Newport, right in the
Just an awesome man while I'm missing, but this bright brand is a good man.
Thank you, Neil.
Any other announcements?
City manager communication?
Just one quick thing.
I wanted to follow up with what we mentioned before about the traffic signal set
B.J. Tunnel in Main Street.
So the traffic signal and that's our goal that was it.
But it's approximately 80s out.
Talk to the contractor yesterday.
Most of the traffic signals that come into the US come through Houston.
And the language of that.
Obviously with her being for two weeks.
So I think I backed up because of that.
So now they're back running.
But there's working to get a lot of new different parts out.
Next week, we have, and I'm proud to say this.
We have a temporary driver's and I'll come it down.
And we are going to try to wire that work.
We gave it all of our signals.
So we can go back to our great normal.
So talk to what actually got damaged then.
This is actually drove over the map like the full and the map.
We're like, okay.
They knock the whole thing down.
Right.
So it's not just how we got a bad pull.
We need to hang it in the right on.
We've destroyed light, wiring, everything.
Okay.
And new this is say we've got their insurance information.
Thank you.
One final thing I had that I wanted to ask about.
Next week we have a study session scheduled.
But our study sessions are set at four.
And Vicki, that's probably going to be hard for you to get.
I'm going to be sitting next weekend.
But I'm even talking about it in the future.
It probably depends on what school's on.
It's probably going to be hard for you to get your four claw.
So would you like me to put an item on,
where we shift those back to 530 because that
we're just going to have to cancel and have special meetings.
I mean, you're not at a count.
Vicki, what's a realistic time.
You could make it here about speed and get my ticket.
How old are you?
1415.
So if we send 430.
We change it to 430.
Okay.
Because I just like to do that.
So we're not doing that all the time.
And it just fits in your schedule and everybody else is calling.
Look at that for the next couple at least.
Okay.
Less the year.
I'll have you.
I want to approach it.
But it's easy for me.
So it's really.
You have to go home and not fall asleep on the couch.
I'm going to get permission.
Okay.
So anything else?
Well, that's it for me. Do you have most two-jour, post-jour, and a second.
Second. Work out, please.